Finding Aid for the Bert Shefter Motion Picture and Television Music Collection PASC-M.0084
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bert Shefter motion picture and television music
circa 1953-circa 1969
UCLA Library Special Collections
Shefter, Bert
PASC-M.0084
43 linear feet (86 boxes)
9 audiovisual carriers (2 records, 7 open reel audiotapes)
4 linear feet (2 unprocessed flat boxes, 1 unprocessed record box)
The collection consists of music manuscrips and tapes of Shefter's compositions for film and television, including Maverick, Sugarfoot's theme, Cheyenne, Colt 45, Five guns to Tombstone, and Harbor lights. The collection is in the midst of being processed. The finding aid will be updated periodically.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Bert Shefter; gift; 1989.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9929768713606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Biographical Note
Bert Abram Shefter was born on May 15, 1904 in Poltova, Russia; attended Carnegie Institute of Technology, Curtis Institute of Music, and the Damrosch Institute; formed a piano duo with Morton Gould (Shefter & Gould); conducted his own orchestra, featuring his own compositions and arrangements on numberous radio commercial shows; musical director of radio station WINS in New York City; guest conductor at Carnegie Hall, 1946-67; made recordings for Victor, Decca and Brunswick; his songs and instrumental works include Haydn seek, Twilight serenade, and Boogie woogie etudes; film scores include: Deerslayer, The return of the fly, Misty, Voyage to the bottom of the sea, The big show, and The big parade; television music includes 77 Sunset Strip, Maverick, Hawaiian eye, Surfside six, and Cheyenne.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of music manuscrips and tapes of Shefter's compositions for film and television, including Maverick, Sugarfoot, Cheyenne, Colt .45, Five Guns to Tombstone, Harbor Lights, She-Devil, Miracle of the Hills, Thunder Island, Six Days to Hell, Police Dog Story, Curse of the Fly, Ambush at Cimarron Pass, The Tall Texan, Misty, and others.
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Projects
Series 2. Musical Compositions
Series 3. Sound Recordings
Motion picture music.; Sawtell, Paul, 1906-1971; Shefter, Bert
- 8196-8267, 8268-8318, 8319-8355, 8357-8414 (Box 86)
  Scope and Contents note
  4 items.
- F614 13120-13133, TR13113-13136 (2 copies), F615 13134(8685)-13141(8690), TR13137-13162, TR13137-13162, F637 13142(8691)-131156(8695) (Box 77)
  7 items.
- F635 13194-13194, F621 13200(8727)-13205(8735), RE13204-220 (2 copies), F624 13206(8734)-13213(8667), F647 13214(8667)-13221(8674) (Box 79)
  6 items.
- F639 13157-13163, TR13163-13187, F619 13172-13187, TR13163-13187, TR13188-13203 (2 copies), TR13190-19193 (Box 78)
- F713 13017(8478)-13033(8504), F715 13034(8506)-13042(8518), F711 13043(8528)-13065(8554), TR13029-13065, TR13066-13093, F649 13066(8566)-13078(8579), F654 13079(8583)-13095(8592) (Box 75)
- GF738 TR9150-TR9161 (2 copies), GF739 TR9111-TR9122 (2 copies), GF740 TR9123-TR9140 (2 copies), SS9262A-9264G (Box 70)
- L.Z.2, L.Z.3, L.Z. 4, F638-652, TR13433, TR13419-432 (2 copies) (Box 83)
- L.Z.5, L.Z.6, L.Z.7, L.Z.8, L.Z.9, Walter Green 28. Walter Green 29, Walter Green 30, Walter Green 31, Walter Green 32, Walter Green 33, Walter Green 34, Walter Green 35, Walter Green 36, Walter Green 37, Walter Green 38, Walter Green 39, Walter Green 40, Walter Green 41, Walter Green 42 (Box 84)
  20 items.
- TR10001-10021, TR10001-10026, TR10022-042, TR10027-10061 (2 copies), TR10043-067, TR10062-084 (Box 71)
- TR10062-10084, TR10085-10107 (2 copies), TR10085-100, TR10108-10131 (2 copies), TR10199-138 (Box 72)
- TR10132-10147 (2 copies), TR10139-152, TR10148-10157 (2 copies), TR10153-157 (2 copies) (Box 73)
- TR10501-10530, TR10531-10563, TR11001-11042, TR11043-11089, TR12001, F658 13010(8466)-13016(8477), TR13000-13028 (Box 74)
- TR13094-13112 (2 copies), F659 13096(8593), F665 13097(8594)-13102(8601), F641 13103-13104, F701 13105(8602)-13112(8616), F709 13113(8607)-13119 (Box 76)
- TR13221-246, TR13221-246. F696 13222(8411)-13235(8432), F699 13236(8433)-13243(8451), F654 13244(8388)-13253(8399), F656 13254(8401)-13260(8410), 13261(8629)-13269(8644A) (Box 80)
- TR13247-13269, TR13270-13291, F705 13270(8645)-13278(8666), F707 13279(8675)-13291, TR13292-13331 (2 copies), TR13385-13418 (Box 81)
- TR13332-13351 (2 copies), TR13352-384 (3 copies), TR13385-13418 (2 copies) (Box 82)
- Walter Green 43, Walter Green 44, W.G.6191A Lonely cowboy, 8000-8025, 8026-8084, 8086-8139, 8140-8195 (Box 85)
- Projects, Series 1.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - 77 Sunset Strip, manuscript; ozalid copy (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Adventures of the Falcon, 1954; autographed manuscript (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Ambush at Cimmaron Pass, manuscript in pencil; ozalid; full score (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Barney Ross Story, The, ozalid master (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Big Circus, The, ozalid master (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Miscellaneous songs with copyright registration forms.
  - Big Circus, The, audio tape (Box 31, Folder 1)
    General note
    Three reels.
  - Big Show, The, manuscript; ozalid master and copy (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Big Show, The, audio tape (Box 31, Folder 2)
    Four reels.
  - Black Scorpion, ozalid master and copy (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bronco, manuscript; ozalid copy (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Cage of Evil, 1960; ozalid copy (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cattle Empire, manuscript in pencil; ozalid copy (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cattle King, 10" open reel audio tapes (Box 32, Folder 1)
    4 tapes
  - Cheyenne (Warner Bros. Television), manuscript in pencil; ozalid copy (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Main title and end title.
  - Cheyenne: The Long Rope (Warner Bros. Teleivsion), ozalid master (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Christine Jorgensen Story, ozalid master; ozalid copy; part and full score (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Christine Jorgensen Story, audio tape (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - The Christine Jorgensen Story (Box 29, Folder 5)
    Scope and Contents
    1 reel.
  - Colt .45 (Warner Bros. Television), ozalid copy (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Various episodes
  - Cosmic Man, manuscript (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Counterplot, manuscript in pencil and ink; ozalid copy; ozalid master; parts (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Counterplot, manuscript in pencil; ozalid master; ozalid copy (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Curse of the Fly, 1964; ozalid copy (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Curse of the Fly (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Deerslayer, manuscript in pencil (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dog of Flanders, manuscript in pencil; ozalid master; ozalid copy (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Five Guns to Tombstone, 1960; ozalid master and copy (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Five Guns to Tombstone, audio tape (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Five Steps to Terror, ozalid master and copy (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Frontier Uprising, audio tape (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Ghost Driver, The, manuscript; ozalid copy (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Great Jesse James Raid, The, manuscript (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Harbor Lights, ozalid master and copy; scores (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Harbor Lights (Box 33)
  - Harbor Lights, 10" open reel audio tapes (Box 44)
    Two reels.
  - reel 1, audio tape (Box 53)
  - House on Airport Drive, 1960; ozalid copy (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Jack the Giant Killer, ozalid master (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Jack the Giant Killer, ozalid copy (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Jack the Giant Killer, ozalid master (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Jack the Giant Killer, audio tape (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Jack the Giant Killer, audio tape (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Jack the Giant Killer, 10" open reel audio tapes (Box 33)
  - King Gun, ozalid master (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Kronos, manuscript (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Last Gun in Durrango, ozalid master and copy; lead sheets (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Last Man on Earth, ozalid master (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Last Man on Earth, Two reels. (Box 34)
  - Last Shot, audio tape (Box 34, Folder 3)
    2 reels.
  - Last Shot You Hear, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Only Yesterday, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 8)
    From the film, "The Last Shot You Hear."
  - Only Yesterday, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Lawman, manuscript; ozalid copy (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Long Rope, The, manuscript; ozalid master and copy (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Long Rope, audio tape (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Long Rope, audio tape (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Lost World, cue sheets; ozalid (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Orchestration by Sid Cutner.
  - Machete, manuscript in pencil; ozalid copy (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - El Marcado, ozalid master; lead sheets (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - El Marcado, ozalid copy; cue sheets (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - El Marcado, manuscript; cue sheet (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Marcado, El, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 15)
    Reel three.
  - Marcado, El, three audio tapes (Box 28)
  - Marcado, El, audio tape (Box 34, Folder 1)
    3 reels.
  - Marked for Glory, audio tape (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Maverick, manuscript; ozalid copy (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Miracle of the Hills, manuscript; ozalid master and copy (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Misty, ozalid copy (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "M.O.", manuscript and ozalid master (Box 17, Folder 1)
    General
    This might be The Last Man on Earth (1964), as the score makes references to vampires.
  - Monster, The, manuscript and ozalid master (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Motor Psycho (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Motor Psycho, audio tape (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Naked Terror, audio tape (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Noose for a Gunman, manuscript; ozalid master and copy (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Outcast, manuscript in pencil; ozalid master; ozalid copy (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Outcast, audio tape (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Outlaws Are in Town, The, 1958; manuscript; ozalid master and copy (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Pete Kelly's Blues, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Song "I Remember Tomorrow."
  - Police Dog Story, ozalid opy; cue sheets (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - El Relicario, manuscript (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Return of the Fly, ozalid master and copy (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sad Horse, The, ozalid master and copy; sheet music (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Sad Horse, audio tape (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - She Devil, autographed manuscript; ozalid copy (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Sierra Baron, manuscript (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Speak of the Devil, audio tape (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Act II.
  - Speak of the Devil, audio tape (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Sugarfoot (Warner Bros. Television), manuscript in pencil; ozalid copy (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sugarfoot, autographed manuscript; ozalid copy (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Sugarfoot, manuscript; ozalid copy (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Tall Texan, The, manuscript (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Tess of the Storm Country, 1960; ozalid copy (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Thunder Island, manuscript and ozalid master (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Thunder Island, audio tape (Box 37, Folder 2)
    4 reels.
  - Phillip Lambro Cues, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Theme no. 2 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified Film Music (probably The Tall Texan and The Great Jesse James Raid), manuscript (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Wild Harvest, ozalid copy (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Wild Harvest, audio tape (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Wild Harvest, audio tape (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Wild Harvest (Box 38)
  - Woman Confidential, 1960; manuscript; ozalid master and copy (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Young Guns of Texas, audio tape (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Young Guns of Texas, audio tape (Box 38, Folder 2)
- Musical Compositions, Series 2.
  - Assorted Materials (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Miscellaneous songs, lead sheets and orchestrations.
  - Assorted Materials, manuscript; ozalid master and copy; sheet music (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Arranged or composed by Bert Shefter.
  - Attya, manuscript (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - David Saperton (Box 26, Folder 11)
    Gadowsky, Leopold studies.
  - I Can't Give You Anything But Love, manuscript (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - I Got Rhythm, manuscript (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - I'm in the Mood For Love, manuscript (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Jealousy, manuscript (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Jususita, manuscript (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Night and Day, manuscript (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Tema Tangi (from the film Hell Ship Mutiny), manuscript in pencil; ozalid copy (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tico Tico, manuscript (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Vicuni Drums, manuscript and ozalid master (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Vicuni Drums, manuscript; ozalid master; full score and parts (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Sound Recordings, Series 3.
  - 10001 - 10107, audio tape (Box 61)
  - 10085 - 10153, audio tape (Box 62)
  - 10531 - 13016, audio tape (Box 63)
  - 13017 - 13095, audio tape (Box 64)
  - 13039 - 13141, audio tape (Box 65)
  - 13137 - 13189, audio tape (Box 66)
  - 13190 - 13246, audio tape (Box 67)
  - 13222 - 13291, audio tape (Box 68)
  - 13292 - 13332, audio tape (Box 69)
  - 13352 - 13233, audio tape (Box 70)
  - 50th Anniversary, audio tape (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Concert at Juilliard.
  - 8213, audio tape (Box 55)
    duplicate
  - 8745 - 8824, audio tape (Box 56)
  - 8825 - 8939, audio tape (Box 57)
  - 8928; 9033, audio tape (Box 58)
  - 9034 - 9049 A, audio tape (Box 59)
  - 9101 - 9264, audio tape (Box 60)
  - Accordion and Violin, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Beethoven, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Beethoven and Francescatti, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Bert and Endre, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Bridges (Box 40)
  - Camp, audio tape (Box 38, Folder 3)
    1 reel
  - Chases (Box 39)
  - Chopin Piano Music, audio tape (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - David Saperton, four audio tapes (Box 26)
    Chopin etudes.
  - Degas, 10" open reel audio tapes (Box 32)
  - Deutch Fiddler, audio tape (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Dick Mark, audio tape (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Dramatic (Box 40)
  - Dramatic 8218 - 8313, audio tape (Box 53)
  - Electric Piano (Box 26)
  - Electric Piano, three audio tapes. (Box 27)
  - Gadowsky, audio tape (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Hindemith and Castelnuovo-Tedesco (Box 36)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Audio tapes.
  - j2pp-0780 -- j2pp-5089-2, audio tape (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Joe Myron, audio tape (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - John Vincent Concert, audio tape (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Juilliard Concert, 1974 June 17; audio tape (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, audio tape (Box 26, Folder 15)
    With E. Manson.
  - Mark, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Mona Golabeck, audio tape (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Concert at UCLA.
  - Mysterioso (Box 40)
  - Mysterioso 8364 - 8382, audio tape (Box 53)
  - New Perspectives in Piano Sounds, audio tape (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Piano Solo, audio tape (Box 30)
  - Solo Piano, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - ss 1136 - 1689, audio tape (Box 46)
  - ss 1690 - 1889, audio tape (Box 47)
  - ss 1890 - 2111, audio tape (Box 48)
  - J08P 3352 - 3353; J2PP 0780; J2PP 5089; J2PP 5508-5509; Bridges; Fight, audio tape (Box 41)
  - ss 3068 3453, audio tape (Box 50)
  - ss 320 - 342; 1847 - 1865; 3401 - 3424, audio tape (Box 53)
  - ss 3454 - 3475, audio tape (Box 51)
  - ss 30 - 57; J2PP 0781; J2PP 5090; J2PP 5492 - 5493; J2PP 5496 - 5497; J2PP 5500 - 5501, audio tape (Box 42)
  - ss 58 - 100; ss 160 - 185; ss 110; ss 199-c, audio tape (Box 43)
  - ss 6000 - 6121, audio tape (Box 51)
  - ss 6122 - 6202, 8000, 14000 - 14026, audio tape (Box 52)
  - ss 201 - 284, audio tape (Box 44)
  - ss 285 - 319; ss 343 - 408, audio tape (Box 45)
  - Tama Tangi, audio tape (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Tana Tangi, audio tape (Box 53)
  - tr 8000 j - 8250, audio tape (Box 54)
  - Unidentified Reels, Five unidentified reels. (Box 28)
  - Unidentified Reels, audio tape (Box 30)
    Eleven unidentified reels.
  - United Producers, audio tape (Box 27, Folder 4)